约翰休斯作品
Captioning sponsored by PARAMOUNT
(rock music playing)
?
片名：红粉佳人
? Caroline laughs and it's raining all day ?
? She loves to be one of the girls ?
? She lives in the place in the side of our lives ?
? Where nothing is ever put straight ?
? She turns herself round and she smiles and she says ?
? "This is it, that's the end of the joke" ?
? And loses herself in her dreaming and sleep ?
? And her lovers walk through in their cloaks ?
? She's... ?
? Pretty in pink
老爸 7点半了!
Daddy, it's 7:30!
? Pretty in pink...
老爸 7点半了!
Daddy, it's 7:30!
爸 起床了!
Daddy, wake up!
早啊 爸爸 快起床
Morning, Daddy. Come on, wake up.
快点起床
Wake up. Come on, wake up.
Come on, wake up.
- 这是你的咖啡 - 我在哪儿?
There's your coffee right there.
Where am I?
把这个喝了
Here. I want you to drink this.
接着洗洗澡穿好衣服 你的衣服在这
Then I want you to take a shower.
Then I want you to get dressed.
之后去找那女人面试 你答应过今天去的
There are your clothes right there.
And then I want you to go see the woman
about the job, okay?
我知道 要不是你在我耳边嗦 我能做点什么?
Today, you promised. I know.
What would I do without you nagging me
你真的想让我回答?
all the time?
You really want me to answer that?
God, I been getting in kind of late lately.
我最近回来的晚 我们没多少机会聊天
We haven't had a chance to talk, or anything.
别担心 也没多少可说的
Well, don't worry about it.
There hasn't been a lot to say.
- 你好吧 - 没事
Is everything all right with you?
- 学校还好吧 - 不好 一直就这样呗
Yeah.
Is school good?
No, but it never is.
- 有人邀请你去毕业舞会吗? - 还没有
Have you been asked
to the prom? No.
上次我说你美呆了是什么时候
When was the last time I told you
昨天吧
how beautiful you are?
About yesterday.
- 转过去 - 干嘛
Hey, hey, turn around.
让我看看你的美衫
What? You know what.
Come here, let me see this outfit.
- 这是你最新的创作? - 就是它了
Is this your latest creation?
天哪 花了多少钱
Uh-huh.
This is it.
My God, what did that cost you?
二手鞋15块 其他是我自己做的
Oh, about $15 for the shoes, secondhand and I made the rest.
太给力了
Unbelievable.
我觉得这玩意你也能利用利用
I was thinking, maybe, that, um,
you could do something with this.
- 这里加点花边… - 快起来
Maybe put some ruffles up here.
我是说真的 这对我意味重大
Come on, get up!
Really, I mean it.
我对我现在的生活满意极了
This means a lot to me.
Honey, I'm perfectly happy
with what I'm doing.
对兼职满意极了?
You're perfectly happy with part-time work?
- 不 所以我才要起床 - 好了 给你做点早饭
No.
That's why I'm getting up.
Okay.
I'll make some breakfast.
我起来了
I'm up!
?
- 嗨 布兰 - 凯特 你好吗
Hi, Blane.
- 很好 你呢 - 不错
Hi, Kate, how you doing?
Fine. How are you? Good.
早啊 欢迎开始新一天的高等教育
'Morning!
Welcome to another day of higher education.
- 唐老鸭 你好吗 - 我在这个垃圾场里混的还不赖
Hi, Duckie, how are you?
Mm, not all that bad, considering I'm in this dump.
你今天穿的真是像火山一样爆发
You know, this is a really volcanic ensemble
- 火山? - 你知道的 火辣 危险…
you're wearing; it's really marvelous.
Volcanic? Well, you know,
- 今天要上课吗 - 我不知道我在情感上有没有准备好
hot, dangerous.
Are you going to class today?
Well, I don't know if I'm emotionally ready.
去上吧 其实不疼的
Oh, go for it-- it's virtually painless.
(class bell rings) Excuse me.
- 我走了 午饭时见 - 好
I gotta go, okay. I'll see you at lunch. Okay.
我打电话给餐厅订位 窗边两位
Well, listen, I'll call ahead
to the cafeteria and make a couple of reservations.
好的
You know, two by the window.
你不喜欢坐在阳光下 好吧 别的呢
Sure. Ah, well, no,
you don't like to sit in the sun.
我今天可以再次崇拜你吗
Okay, something else. Uh, listen, may
I admire you again today?
女士们 我可能分身乏力
Ah, ladies, ladies, uh, listen,
让你们俩或其中之一到放假时怀孕
I may be able to work out a deal where either one,
or the both of you, could be pregnant by the holidays.
What do you say?
(girls snicker)
有人认为新政拯救了资本主义体系
Some argue that The New Deal saved the capitalist system.
有证据显示罗斯福政府
And as evidence
that the Roosevelt administration was trying
比起培育社会主义思想
to avoid excessive governmental power.
更尽力避免造成集权政府
Rather than implant socialism,
罗斯福当上总统的第一项法案
in his first act as president,
就是《紧急银行法》
Mr. Roosevelt enacted The Emergency Banking Act,
而且他拒绝国有化
and he refused to consider nationalization.
你衣服是哪买的 旧货市场吗 真好看!
Where'd you get your clothes,
five and dime store?
KATE (snickering): Attractive.
有问题吗 女士们
Is there a problem,
- 没有 - 没有
ladies?
No!
KATE: No.
Andie, is there something going on between you
安迪 你和这两位女士之间有矛盾吗
没有 我没觉得有
and these ladies?
No, not that I'm aware of.
我要代表斯楚马妮小姐和亨森小姐道歉
I'd like to apologize on behalf
of Miss Trombley and Miss Hanson.
她们在今晚写着
These two young ladies will be thinking of you tonight
我们讲过的这几章的摘要时会想着你的
as they write a summary of the chapters
that we've just covered.
太好了!
Great.
- 不好意思 - 怎么
Excuse me.
Yeah.
Um, there's nothing wrong with me, I mean, I fine.
我没什么 我很好 摘要的事就算了吧
Can you just forget about the chapter?
- 怎么 - 摘要我们写了
Yes?
We'll take the chapter.
好了 继续讲
Fine. Let's go on.
《紧急银行法》
The Emergency Banking Act.
回见
(rock music playing)
See you guys later.
安迪 你太美了
Oh, Andie, you look ravishing.
我们过一个月就要毕业了
So, we graduate in a month.
我们要不要一起做点神马?
Now, I want to know when it is you
and I are going to get together and do something?
千万不要
Try never.
- 我可不仅仅是说性 - 是的
Well, I'm talking about more than sex here.
我喜欢了你四年 你一直理都不理我
No, you're not.
You know, I've liked you for four years
and you treat me like shit, you know.
我就不明白了 你有什么毛病
I don't, I don't understand that.
离我车远一点好不?
What's your problem?
Can you get off of my car?
这学校的女孩我钓了不少
You know, I've been out
with a lot of girls at this school.
- 你有什么特殊的 - 我有点品味
I don't see what makes you so different.
I have some taste.
你是个贱人
You're a bitch.
你应该去看医生 你的情况可能会越来越糟
You know, I think you ought to see a doctor,
'cause that condition of yours
can get a lot worse.
(door closes, engine starts)
(buzz of conversation)
(staple gun snapping )
鼓掌 鼓掌 鼓掌
Applause, applause, applause.
真漂亮 这真是太…
This is beautiful.
现代了
It's so... modern.
是不是美呆了
I mean, is this fab, or what?
很好看
It's great.
- 我真是非常非常擅长装饰 - 我知道
I'm very, very good at this.
我穿这种零售衣服真是浪费
I know.
Such a waste
that I run a lowly little retail outlet.
- 要是搭的好就没问题 - 我床上功夫厉害 我该去当鸡吗?
No, not if you're good at it.
I'm good in bed. Should I be a whore?
不错
It's great.
Mmmm.
- 你参加过毕业舞会? - 是的
Did you say that you went to your prom?
Yeah, sure.
- 好玩不 - 史上最烂
Was it terrible?
但本来就是这样的 你应该去 是不是
It was the worst.
But it's supposed to be,
you know what I mean.
不是必须去的 又不是强制要求
But you have to go, right?
Well, you don't have to.
I mean, it's not a requirement.
我有个女朋友就没去
I have this girl friend who didn't go to hers,
她经常会有很不好的感觉 就像丢东西了
and every once in a while
she gets this really terrible feeling,
you know, like something is missing.
她检查钱包和钥匙 数数孩子少没少 她会抓狂
She checks her purse, you know, she checks her keys,
she counts her kids, she goes crazy,
之后她意识到…
and then she realizes that...
什么都没少
nothing is missing.
她觉得这就是没去毕业舞会的后遗症
She decided it was side effects from skipping the prom.
我也不知道 我的一部分让我直接过去就完了
I don't know, I mean,
part of me says just go and get it over with,
另一部分觉得这是个愚蠢的传统又没有意义
and this other part of me says it's a stupid tradition
你知道
and what's the point?
Well, you know,...
生命本来就是个愚蠢的传统
you could say that life itself is a... stupid tradition,
别分析了 去就是了
but don't analyze it; just go.
(lid opening)
放回去!
Put that back!
- 只差一英季褪俏业难劬! - 半英
You missed my eye by an inch!
Half an inch.
这里不是公共图书馆 小偷!
IONA: This ain't the public library,
(shop bell tinkling) light fingers!
我去接!
(phone rings) I'll get it.
泰克丝 你想肿么样
IONA: Trax, what do you want?
泰龙 你弄砸了
IONA: Tyrone, you blow.
是的 我在上班 别烦我
Yeah, I'm working.
Leave me alone!
(fake laugh)
真刺激!
That's thrilling!
我给你煮饭 给你洗衣服 还跟你睡觉
I cook for you, I do your laundry,
现在你想找人送你上班?
I sleep with you, now you want a ride
to work?!
长大点吧!
Please, grow up!
坐公车…
Take the bus!
Take a cab!
你好吗
How you doing?
- 好啊 - 不错
Fine. Good.
- 要帮忙吗 - 好的
Can I help you?
- 能给我提供点意见吗 - 可能
Yeah. Yeah.
Can I get your opinion on something here?
Maybe.
可能
这个好吗
This any good?
IONA: Sticks and stones, Tyrone.
很热 白热化
It's hot. IONA:Sticks and stones.
White-hot.
很好 我要了
Good. I'll take it.
Okay, um, will that be cash or charge?
好的 现金还是刷卡
美国运通白金卡?
American Express Platinum Card,
maybe?
现金
IONA: Take a bus to the zoo!
要知道 你每次上完厕所 智商都会下降
Cash.
IONA: You know...
every time you go to the john, you lose IQ points.
是Walter Mondale(美国副总统)
(whispering): It's Walter Mondale.
- 7块5 这是找零 - 谢谢
And...
$7:50 is your change.
Thanks.
IONA: Tyrone... no.
- 我不要袋子 - 不要?
I don't need a bag.
No? No.
IONA: I can't do these things for you.
- 谢谢 - 好好听
Thanks. Enjoy it.
Thanks.
(door opens, shop bell tinkles)
我的生活中没有束缚 从什么时候开始
IONA: Bondage has no place in my life.
(bell tinkles, door closes)
从我被绑在你的车后座那一夜开始!
Since when?
Since I spent the night tied up in the backseat of your car!
? I stuck my head out of an empty room ?
? Expectin' nothin' but the new room view ?
? I swear I saw the future below me ?
? Spitting in the face of doom
? Yes, so I'm sayin' ?
? Tonight ?
? Whoa, tonight
? Rudy, come on and rule it tonight ?
? Tonight ?
? Yeah, tonight
? Rudy, come on and rule it tonight ?
? Tonight ?
? Rudy... ? Tonight... ?
- 詹娜 - 干嘛
Jena? Yeah.
你有没考虑过跟有钱人出去?
Well, would you ever consider going out
with somebody that had money?
我觉得这没什么区别 我是说…
I don't think it makes a difference.
I mean... it's material.
物质而已
西蒙! 西蒙!
Simon?
要是你爸搭上个有钱人回家 你会怎么办?
Simon!
What would you do if your father came home a rich man?
- 拍他马屁 - 你看吧
Kiss his ass.
- 看什么? - 西蒙刚刚说的
See?
See what?
What Simon just said.
怎么…
What S...
你什么意思 你已经跟富人出去了?
Andie, what are you getting at?
Are you... are you going out with a rich guy or something?
- 我走了 - 嘿 还没回答问题呢
I got to go.
Hey, wait, wait! You didn't answer my question.
- 没有 - 很好
No!
西蒙 好刺激
Good.
Simon, it's been stimulating.
- 我来这儿多久了? - 不知道 有几年了
How long I been coming here?
I don't know, a couple years.
- 那我们就是伙计了 我们很熟 - 是的 哥们
Okay, so, you know, we're buddies.
We're close, right?
好吧 那你放我进去过几次?
Oh, yeah, oh, yeah.
Very, pal.
Okay, so how many times have you let me in?
- 我不会放你进去的 你知道的 - 我就是这个意思
I never let you in. You know that.
- 不知道 哪个意思 - 我女朋友在里面 而我在外面…
You see, you see what I'm saying?
I don't know. What are you saying?
What I'm saying is, my girlfriend is in there,
她是女的 还是我朋友 所以她是我女朋友
and I'm out here.
Well, she's a girl, and she's my friend,
但她在里面 我在外面 你是个敏锐 性感的大家伙
so she's a girl friend,
but she's in there, and I'm out here!
I mean, you're a sensitive,
- 你知道这很伤人的! - 我认真地问你个问题
sexually potent kind of guy.
You got to know how that hurts.
Well, let me ask you a question seriously.
她知道我不会让你进去 为什么还过来
Why does she come here, knowing I don't let you in?
- 你想想 - 我不知道
Huh? Think about it.
I don't know.
总之 我给你的建议就是…
(laughs)
All right, my advice to you is, uh...
甩了她 你不需要她
dump her, lose her.
明白我想表达的意思吗
You don't need that.
You see what I'm saying?
You see the point I'm trying to make?
爱情是狗娘 唐老鸭 爱情是狗娘
Love's a bitch, Duck.
Love's a bitch.
- 这不是真理吧 - 是真理
Ain't it the truth, ain't it the truth.
- 击掌 - 好的!
Oh, it's the truth. High five.
All right. Go for it.
抽根烟试试?
Hey, want to try a cigarette? Come on.
宝贝 问你个私人问题
Oh, the babe, the babe, the babe.
Hey, honey, honey, let me ask you a personal question.
如果你崇拜唐老鸭 为啥不去个他能进去的地方
If you worship the Duck,
why don't you hang out somewhere he could get in, I mean...
好个骰子人 跟你老婆孩子问好 知道我什么意思吗
Dice, Dice Man, hey!
Say hello to the wife and kids.
他诵读困难 他理解的东西是反的 他是想说…
You know what I'm saying? Yeah.
You see, the Dice Man is dyslexic.
He gets everything backwards.
- 好了 唐老鸭 - 你确定?
What he meant to say was, like, if I worship...
因为他要是惹你不高兴了 我要用他的屁股扫干净整个停车场
It's okay, Duckie.
Okay, 'cause... you're sure, because if he offended you,
- 我很好 不用担心我 - 好的
I would gladly clean up this parking lot with his butt.
No, I'm fine. Don't worry about it.
- 你来很久了吗? - 没 也就三四个小时而已
Okay, okay. Were you here long?
Nah, nah, three, four hours.
玩的开心吗?
You have a good time, at least?
- 很好 现在怎么办 - 上床
Uh-huh.
Oh, good. That's good. Now, what now?
你的还是我的?
Bed.
- 我们的? - 有创意
Yours, or mine?
Ours? Nice try.
好了 送我回家好吗
Okay. Can you at least give me a ride home?
好 上车
Yeah. Get in.
Aha. Can I, like, put my head in your lap?
我能把头放在你腿上吗?
我能不能在你开车时头靠着你肩膀
No, wait. Can I rest my head on your shoulder
- 上车 唐老鸭 - 好的
and let you steer?
Get in, Duckie. Okay.
(instrumental rock music playing)
(tape squealing)
这些房子好漂亮 唐老鸭
(jazzy instrumental rock playing)
ANDIE: These houses are amazing, Duck.
我赚到了第一桶金就给你买一幢 我讨厌这首歌
DUCKIE: Hey, the first million I make, I buy you one.
- 好漂亮 - 你想要美 照镜子就好了
I hate this song.
They're so beautiful! (tape squealing)
Hey, you want beauty, look in the mirror.
(indistinct rock vocal plays)
整张专辑都好恐怖
This whole tape is horrible. (tape squealing)
(instrumental rock music plays)
肯定是荷尔蒙作祟 每首歌都让我想吐
I-I must be going through, like, a hormone thing,
'cause every song I listen to is making me sick.
我怎么就找不到一首好歌
I mean, why can't I find a decent song here?
- 这是我最喜欢的 - 你聋了?
That one's my favorite.
这座房子!
Are you deaf?
The house!
是个不错的小摇篮
Oh, yeah, yeah, that's, that's...
That's a nice little, little crib.
我想知道那里面是什么样的
Wonder what it's like inside.
那又怎么了
Well, what-what difference does it make?
知不知道伤心之处是什么
You know what the really sad thing is, though?
我打赌住在里面的人不会觉得 它有我眼里的一半好看
I bet the people that live there don't think
it's half as pretty as I do.
要知道 安迪 我…
You know what I mean?
You know, Andie, I'm just...
他们不像过去那样会写情歌了 我…
They just don't write love songs like they used to.
It's... I-I... Oh.
我现在不高兴了 我晚上要打针 快送我回家
I'm angry about this, you know?
I... this...
My evening's shot. I...
Just drive me home now.
(computer keyboards clicking)
(woman speaking quietly)
(indistinct, overlapping chatter)
WOMAN: That's... That's right.
(keys clicking, indistinct chatter)
(sighs)
(keys clicking)
WOMAN: All right.
(typing)
(beeping)
我过来并不仅仅是想打个招呼
DUCKIE: Well, the reason I came over--
I mean, other than I've been planning to come by
- 我是想跟你谈谈安迪 - 是吗
and just say hello--
I wanted... I wanted to talk to you about Andie.
她是个不可思议的人 你知道的
Yeah?
I mean, she's... she's an incredible individual.
我是说 我会一直陪着她的 不管什么时候 以何种方式 我一直会的
I mean, you know that.
I mean, I'm there for her!
你可以放心 我会一直保护她
Whenever, however, I'm there.
You can rest assured that she's covered.
你不用担心 因为我唯一的计划
I don't want you to worry,
because my only future plans are to make sure
就是要好好照顾她
that she's taken care of.
你真有心 菲尔
That's nice of you, Phil. (clears throat)
我想娶她
And I'd like to marry her.
不是今天 但总有那么一天的
Oh, well, not... you know, not-not today,
安迪知道你的想法吗
but eventually, I figure.
Well, does Andie know how you feel about this?
Uh...
还没有跟她确认过 现在只是在打基础
No confirmation on that just yet.
I mean, I'm-I'm laying the groundwork and everything.
我指的是房子 食物 基本需求
You know, I'm thinking in terms of housing,
you know, food, basic needs type of stuff, but
但我会找个好时机的
I'm picking my moment.
- 你能理解吧 - 当然
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, I mean, you understand, right?
我对某人也是这般的感觉
(chuckles) Oh, sure.
I felt the same way about somebody myself.
女孩?
Oh, a girl?
是个女孩
A girl.
(laughs)
我爱上她 就娶了她
Um, I loved her, and, uh,
I mar... married her.
有一天她就这么走了
And, uh, one day she just split.
等等 是安迪的妈妈?
Oh, wait. This was... This was Andie's mom?
是的
Yeah.
Oh.
我有三年没见她了 但是…
(laughs)
So, uh, I haven't seen her in, uh, three years, you know,
但我还是一如既往地爱她 知道不
and, um, but I still love her just as...
as much as I ever did, you know?
你可以爱安迪 但这并不意味着她就会爱你
I mean, you can love Andie,
but that doesn't mean she's gonna love you back.
并不意味着她不会 但是…
I mean, doesn't mean that she won't, but, uh,
我是想说一切顺随天意
what I'm trying to say is,
you can't make it happen, you know?
成或不成 不在人力
It either will, or it won't.
- 全要看她的内心 - 是的 在心脏血管里
Uh, it's all in the heart.
Oh, y-yeah, sure.
我明白 我上过学
I... Cardiovascular.
Yeah, I-I understand. I-I...
I've been to school. (chuckles)
Yeah.
我跟个卖真空吸尘器的有约 先走了
Well, uh, I got an appointment with a vacuum cleaner.
Got to go.
你真是家居狂人
Hey, you're on a whole home improvement jag here, aren't you?
- 是的 扭转旧的生活 - 祝你更给力
Yup. Turn the old life around.
Yeah. Well, hey, more power to you.
蒂娜・特纳(美国摇滚教母)做的到的 杰克・韦尔奇(通用电气总裁)也做的到
If Tina Turner can do it, Jack Walsh can do it, too.
谢谢你的陪伴 我很感激
(laughs) Well,
thanks for taking your time.
I really... You know, I-I appreciate it.
- 我的荣幸 - 我像件脏衣服一样走了
My pleasure.
I'm off like a dirty shirt.
(chuckles)
(distant train bell clanging)
蒂娜・特纳
Tina Turner.
(train bell clanging)
(humming)
(instrumental rock music plays)
(door opening, shop bell tinkling)
(door closing, shop bell tinkling)
好啊
Hiya.
(laughs) Hiya.
Um, oh, we just got these glasses in.
我们刚进了这些眼镜 真是太…
我不喜欢那天那张专辑
They're really, um...
Yeah, I didn't like that album I got the other day. ...dumb.
什么
What? What?
- 唱片 - 唱片
The record. Oh, the record.
我觉得有点太…
Uh, yeah, I thought it was a little too, uh...
流行了 可能
Too hip, maybe?
是啊 有点太流行了
Yeah, a little too hip.
能不能推荐点别的 不那么政治的?
ANDIE: Well, um...
BLANE: Think you can recommend something else
a little less political
or something?
- 林昂内尔・里奇? - 不要
Lionel Ritchie?
Nah.
呃…
(sucks air through teeth)
- 蒂娜・玛丽? 麦当娜? - 麦当娜 太高深了
No. Uh, well, hmm...
Tina Marie, Madonna?
Madonna?
Yeah, Madonna.
是的 很高深 但她有独特的个人风格
That's awfully deep.
Yeah, very deep.
But she's got such great style.
听着
Yeah. Yeah, listen, um...
(burglar alarm ringing) Um, that's the alarm.
警报响了 稍等一会吧 我马上回来
Can you hold on for a second?
Sure. Just... I'll, I'll be right back.
你可以读这个 写的很好
Okay.
Here, read this.
It's really good. Don't... No, no, no, you can...
Hold on.
这是啥
What is this?
嗨 今天怎么样
(alarm continues )
(loudly): Hi!
How's your day?!
估计得有300分贝了吧
Baby pumps out about 300 decibels, huh?
- 是你弄的? - 不确定
(alarm stops)
Did you do this?
Well, I'm not sure.
我在用你的洗刷间 我决定不去打扰你
I mean, I was just using your powder room,
and I decided not to disturb you,
所以我要从后门走了 但我肯定碰到了 什么东西
so I was going to go out the back door,
but I guess I must have touched something.
- 你是怎么进来的 - 你生气了?
How'd you get in here? Are you mad?
是 我生气了! 到底都有公共厕所!
Yes, I'm mad!
There are public bathrooms all over the place!
我不是小孩 安迪 这我知道
I'm not nine, Andie. I know that.
现在是月末 已经没有座垫圈了
It's just, it's the end of the month.
They're out of toilet seat covers.
(knocking)
DUCKIE: You know what I stickler I am about personal hygiene.
It's very important to me.
ANDIE: That's ridiculous.
We want you to stop making...
- 布兰 你干啥呢 - 伙计 没啥 瞎转转
Blane, what are you doing?
Hey, buddy, what's up?
- 你要买什么 唱片? - 差不多
Nothing, hanging out.
Well, what are you shopping for, records or something?
- 有收获吗 - 不见得
I guess. You find anything?
No, not really. Not really.
我们去打弹子吧 今天肯定成绩好
Well, are we gonna shoot some track, or what?
'Cause, I mean, if we're gonna shoot, we got to shake it, man.
我没多少地方可去 我喜欢来这里 请原谅
I don't have anyplace to go.
I like coming here. Excuse me very much.
好吧 我也不好意思跟你发火 我得回去了 回见
It's okay. I'm sorry for getting mad at you.
I got to get back out in front, okay?
See you later.
(shop bell tinkling)
这真是个烂警报系统 我开了五次门它才响
(alarm ringing)
This is a shitty alarm system.
I opened and closed the door five times before it rang.
好了 我这就走 我不会再多待了 不可能!
That's it, I'm leaving.
I'm not going to stay here.
No, no way!
(door slams)
(sighs)
嗨 6点05分杜基・戴尔打来 给我回电话
Uh, hi, it's 6:05. Duckie Dale. Give me a call.
(answering machine beeps)
6点15 杜基・戴尔 给我电话
Um, 6:15. Duckie Dale again. Call me, okay?
(beep)
安迪 你在哪儿 我是唐老鸭 给我打电话
(singsongy): Andie, where are you? This is the Duck.
Give me a call, okay?
(beep)
6点28…
Uh, it's 6:28.
求你给我打电话吧 求你求你
(sighs)
Please call, please, please, please!
我是唐老鸭 你是不是在家不接电话
This is Duckie, are you really home and just not picking up?
如果是这样的话 我觉得像个大傻逼
'Cause if so, I feel like a giant asshole here.
6点31 给我回电话吧
It's 6:31, give me a call, okay, please?
(beep)
(phone rings)
唐老鸭 我早上再跟你说 再见
DUCKIE: Andie, this is...
Duckie, I'll just talk to you in the morning, okay?
Bye. (sighs)
(sighs)
(train whistle blowing)
(humming "Santa Lucia")
? Prospero il vento
? Prospero il vento...
- 你怎么起来了 我还没叫你呢 - 我在给你做早饭
What are you doing up?
I didn't wake you up yet.
一个鸡蛋加面包 我喂过狗了
Well, I'm fixing breakfast.
One egg, over-medium, and I fed the dog.
- 爸爸把你喂饱了? - 你的鸡蛋 女士
Oh, did Daddy feed you, huh?
- 我不吃鸡蛋 老爸 - 为什么不吃
Your egg, madame.
Oh, I don't eat eggs, Daddy.
Here, why don't you go in and eat it.
- 我给你拿咖啡和果汁 - 好的
I'll bring you your coffee and juice, okay?
- 你从什么时候开始不吃鸡蛋的? - 从一出生开始 别担心
Okay.
Since when don't you like eggs?
Oh, since about birth.
Don't worry about it.
- 你到底为啥这么早起床 - 早上了啊
Hey, you never told me why you were up.
Well, it's morning.
你是说为啥没用你叫我起床吧
Oh, you mean,
why didn't you have to drag my ass out of bed?
好吧
Okay.
我找到工作了
Well, I gotta job.
- 不是吧? - 正是
No?!
Yeah.
- 在哪儿? - 我上班后再告诉你
Where?!
Um, well, I'll tell you after I start.
- 要等到什么时候? - 很快
When's that?
Soon.
- 我真为你骄傲 你有工作了 - 这算什么
I'm so proud of you!
这很了不起 很了不起
You got the job.
No big deal.
Yes, it is a big deal.
好了 我得走了 上学要迟到了
It's a very big deal.
Listen, I gotta go, okay?
- 今晚再告诉我 - 好的 保证精彩
I'm gonna be late for school.
You tell me all about it tonight.
I'm so proud of you. All right,
it'll be real good.
伙计们
Hi, guys.
- 你好吗 - 挺好 你呢
How you doing?
我挺好
Fine.
And you? Okay.
- 我刚说了我很好了 - 是啊 抱歉
And you?
Well, I just said I was fine.
Oh, yeah. Sorry.
- 这是你第一次出来? - 是的
So, is this your first time out here?
我觉得我在这里也不怎么受欢迎
Yeah.
I don't think I'm very popular out here
不知道 我觉得你挺好啊
either.
Oh, I don't know.
You're just fine inside.
我也不知道 我对这些其实不大感冒 懂不
I don't know.
I'm not really into all their shit, you know.
我懂
Yeah.
(softly): Yeah.
你的电脑把戏不错
Oh, um, I really liked your computer trick.
- 给力吧 - 给力的要命
Clever, huh?
Terribly clever, yeah, terribly.
- 要迟到了吗 - 还真是
Are you late for something?
Yeah, I am, as a matter of fact.
但也没什么
But I mean, it's no big deal.
Um...
周五想出去玩吗
Listen, do you want to... you want to go out Friday?
好的
Yeah.
- 好吗? - 好啊
Yeah?
好!
Sure.
- 7点行不? - 可以
Yeah? Okay! Sure.
Uh, 7:00, okay?
很好 你住在哪儿 我去接你
Yeah, that's fine. Great. Great.
Well, where do you live? I'll pick you up.
- 你住在哪儿 - 不好意思
Where do you live?
Oh, I, I... No, I'm sorry, um,
我周五要工作 去商场接我好了
I'm gonna be working on Friday,
so you can just pick me up at the mall.
- 好的 - 好
Okay. Okay?
- 拜拜 - 再见
Bye.
See ya.
布兰 你好吗
Hey, Blane.
伙计 咋了?
How you doing?
Hey, buddy, what's up?
- 你要干吗 - 没什么 去上课
What are you up to?
我看到你在外面了
Oh, not much. Going to class.
I thought I saw you outside.
- 怎么了? - 怎么 你在干什么
So?
So, what are you doing?
你是谁 我老妈吗? 好了 我走了 回见
What are you, my mother?
Come on, I gotta go.
- 布兰 到底怎么了 - 没什么
I'll see you later. Blane, what's going on?
可不是没什么 我看到你跟那小妞搭话了 她叫啥 艾迪?
Nothing.
Well, not nothing,
I mean, I saw you talking to that chick--
what's her name?-- Eddie or something.
- 关你什么事 - 我最好的朋友跟个怪胎说话
So, what do you care?
Listen, my best friend is conversing with a mutant,
我很好奇 你没必要这么防我
you know, I'm curious.
I don't think that's any reason to get defensive.
我不是防你 我只是碰巧喜欢她 好不?
I'm not defensive.
I just happen to like her, all right?
听着 这是你的生活 跟我无关
Listen, all right, it's you know,,
it's your life, it's none of my business.
You really don't think she's got something?
你就不觉得她很特别?
我真没觉得 对不起了
No.
I really don't, I'm sorry.
你要迟到了 伙计
You're gonna be late, buddy.
(class bell rings)
《华沙条约》是由苏维埃共和国
Okay, the Warsaw Pact's a treaty
和七个东欧国家签订的
that was signed by the Soviet Union
and its seven East European satellites, okay.
它的作用是…
And what it did was...
建立了一个共同的防御组织 也即…
it established a mutual
唐老鸭!
defense organization
怎么了 怎么了 我写了什么
as a counterweight to NATO.
Duckie! What?
What? What? What?
你说"《华沙条约》是以华沙命名的"
Well, what'd I put?
You wrote,
the Warsaw Pact is the pact that's named
after Warsaw.
老师会知道你在胡说八道的
Uh-huh.
So, the teacher's just gonna know
好吧 其他的部分怎么样
that you're just bullshitting.
Okay, okay, what about the rest of it?
俄国革命也并不发生在德国
Well, the Russian Revolution
did not take place in Germany. Ow.
- 那卡尔・马克思是什么人呢? - 他是德国人
Well, what was Karl Marx, then?
- 继续吧 - 但他是德国人
He was a German.
Well, there you go.
Yes, but his being German doesn't have anything
跟俄国革命的发生并没有关系!
to do with where the Russian Revolution occurred.
好吧好吧
Okay, okay.
好吧 我跟你说点事 你别生气行不?
Okay, Duckie, can I propose something to you
without your getting upset, or angry?
- 看情况了 - 什么情况?
Well, that depends.
不知道 我先这么说 你说吧
On what?
I don't know, I just said that.
你是故意考试不及格 以便一直留在高中
Go ahead.
Well, I propose
that you're deliberately flunking your courses
so that you can stay in high school.
滚吧 我为什么这么做?
Get out of here!
- 我不知道 你告诉我 - 我并没这么做 所以没什么好说的
Why, why, why would I do that?
I don't know, you tell me.
Well, I'm not.
So, there's nothing to tell.
- 你总是不愿面对现实 - 我在逃避什么?
Well, you know, you're not always one to face things.
What, since when?
未来
What, what am I not facing?
不管你面不面对现实 它总会发生 知道吗
The future.
Well, whether or not you face the future, it happens,
- 你总是贬低自己 为什么 - 我没有贬低自己!
right?
You run yourself down. Why do you do that?
你觉得我有? 我不觉得我有
I am not running myself...
You think I'm running my...
为什么 因为我的打扮方式? 让我可以嘲笑自己?
I don't think I'm running myself down.
Why b-b-because, because of the way I dress?
这叫做幽默感 你要是有就好了 很美妙的
'Cause, 'cause I can laugh at myself?
That's called a sense of humor.
You should get one; they're nice.
- 我们下年要做什么? - 你觉得我还会在上高中
What are we gonna do next year?
Well, according to you, I'll still be in high school.
我是认真的! 过去这八年里的每一天
No, I'm serious.
I mean, not a day has passed,
我都至少要跟你说20次话!
in, what, eight years, when I didn't see you
这就叫作奉献
or talk to you at least 20 times.
Well, that's devotion.
我知道 有时就算我生气了 你也知道我悄悄地喜欢这感觉
I know, and even though I sometimes get angry,
you know that I secretly love it.
我知道的
You see, I knew that.
You know, I hope I'm not the only one in the world
我希望不止我一个人觉得你给力
that knows what an incredible person you are.
到目前为止 似乎你是唯一一个 宝贝
Well, at this point in time, I'm afraid you are, honey.
我去弄点喝的 之后再学习 好不
Okay, I'm gonna get something to drink
- 听你的 - 你要什么
and then we work, okay, you promise?
Oh, you bet. Okay, what do you want?
- 啤酒 威士忌 果汁 都行 - 好的
Oh, beer, scotch, juice box, whatever.
Okay.
天哪
(sighs)
Oh, God.
我爱她
I love this woman.
我深爱着她 我要告诉她
I love this woman and I have to tell her.
如果她笑了 她笑
And if she laughs, she laughs.
如果她不爱我 那就是不爱我
And if she doesn't love me, she doesn't love me.
但要是我不找出来…
But if... if I don't find out...
我太爱她了!
Oh, I love her too much.
(sighs)
这是真的
? Love is real...
谢谢
(makes sound of crowd)
真实就是爱
Thank you, thank you.
? Real is love...
你是精彩的一员 你知道的
You're a wonderful crowd here, you know that.
爱是生存
(panting)
? Love is living
(imitates crowd noise)
(dog whines)
你很美 我爱你 你很妙 我爱你的头发
(chuckles)
You're fabulous, I do love you,
I do love you, you're gorgeous.
爱是感觉
I love your hair.
? Love is feeling
感觉到爱
? Feeling love
爱是欲望
(laughs)
(dog barking) ? Love is wanting
Ah!
她会笑的 我能怪她吗
She's gonna laugh.
Would I blame her?
- 给 - 谢了 但我得闪了
Here you go. Oh, shit.
Honey, thanks, uh, but I'm gonna split,
- 怎么了 你的论文怎么办? - 就是去搞论文
you know. Why? What about your paper?
Uh, that's, that's what I'm gonna do, you see,
要是你帮我的话 谢谢了 那就不是我的论文了 而是造假
'cause, I mean, if you help me, thanks a lot,
but it'll, it'll,
it won't be my work, it'll be bogus.
明早见了
And, you know, and I guess I'll see you in the a.m..
酒后不驾车 所以我骑自行车
Hey, drinking and driving don't mix.
That's why I ride a bike.
(sighs)
I got it.
(screams)
JENA: So, uh, what's the deal?
你这周末出去吗?
You going out this weekend? I don't know.
还不确定呢
I'm not sure yet. Mm?
- 你打算做什么 - 待在家里
Why? What are you gonna do?
- 是吗 又要开始学习了? - 可能吧 熄了好吗
Stay home. Yeah, you going to study again?
Probably.
Would you put that out? (giggling): No.
为啥这么努力学习? 恶心死了 我就不明白
Well, you study so much, it makes me ill.
不明白? 我不想一辈子都在唱片店工作
I just don't see the point.
You don't? Mm-mmm.
I don't want to work in a record store my whole life.
你想当什么 医生?
Yeah? What do you want to be a doctor?
天哪
(whistle blows) Oh, God.
让我们过去 排好队 谢谢
(sighs)
TEACHER: Okay, let's go, everybody.
Get in your lines, please, thank you!
- 沃米斯特! - 到!
Fulmeister.
巴塞特!
Here.
Besset!
- 巴萨诺 - 有!
Basono!
- 小心 - 我们身上很臭吗
Goulong.
Oh, look, watch out.
Ooh.
Deeds! Do we smell bad, or something?
本尼
(whispering): Hey, Benny.
我希望她们萎缩并掉下来
Fox.
Penfield.
I hope they shrivel up and fall off.
(whistle blows) Okay.
怎么回事 荷曼小姐?
What was that, Miss Hoeman?
Um.
我说"我希望她们萎缩并掉下来"
(clears throat)
I said, I hope they shrivel up and fall off.
你希望什么萎缩并掉下来?
(lightly laughs)
You hope what shrivels up
她的胸 迪兹小姐
and falls off?
Her breasts, Miss Dietz.
- 闭嘴! - 对不起
(laughs)
Shut up! I'm sorry.
你给我出去 荷曼
You are out of here,
好的
Hoeman. Right.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
姑娘们 先走了
Bye, girls.
你跟你同伴持一样的态度吗?
So, uh,
do you share your partner's attitude?
不是的
No, I don't.
吃屎去吧
(under breath): Eat shit!
不好意思 迪兹小姐
Excuse me, Miss Dietz.
你只剩几个月了
You've only got a couple of months left.
你的功课很好
You're doing extremely well in your courses.
我觉得你也很可能获得奖学金
And I think your chances
of getting a scholarship are excellent.
- 我知道 唐纳利先生 - 那这是怎么回事
I know this, Mr. Donnelly.
我也不知道 我只是有点厌倦了
Why are you in here now?
I don't know.
I guess I just got a little fed up.
- 厌倦什么 - 我们遭遇的对待
With what?
The way that we get treated.
听着 你在这里接受的是一流的教育
Look, uh...
you're getting a top-notch education here,
我不想看你就这么前功尽弃
and I just don't want to see you throw it away.
我得到的教育 比我应得的更好
I'm getting a better education than I deserve.
我走运 这个社区的好人允许我来这里上学
I'm lucky.
I'm fortunate that the good people
of this community allow me to attend this school.
- 你又误解我了 - 不 我一切都明白
Again, you are misunderstanding me.
No, I understand everything, Mr. Donnelly.
我不需要你来解释 我就活在这解释里
I don't need to have it explained to me.
只不过我有时会很生气 会发脾气
I live it.
It's just sometimes I get a little upset
and I lose my temper.
我不想看到我的朋友因为维护自己而受罚
I just don't like to see my friends getting dumped on
and punished for defending themselves.
这整件事情就当没发生过 好吗
Well, uh, we'll just forget about this whole thing, okay?
好的
Okay.
詹娜呢?
What about Jena?
- 她也没事 - 谢谢
She's off, too.
Thank you.
安迪
Andie...
如果你一幅不易接近的样子
if you put out signals that you don't want to belong,
人们是不会接近你的
people are going to make sure that you don't.
这理论真妙
That's a beautiful theory.
安迪! 安迪!
Andie, Andie, Andie, listen.
我听说了发生的事 尽快从家政课上赶来了
I heard what happened and, and I came as fast as I could.
- 严重吗? - 没什么
I cut out of home ec and everything.
- 你生气了吗 - 没有
Was, was it really bad?
No, it was nothing. Are you upset?
我看的出来你生气了 你眼睛都斜了
No, I'm not. No-- yes, yes, you are.
I can tell; your eyes get all squinty and everything.
- 我知道怎么能让你感觉好一点 - 我觉得很好!
Listen, I know just what to do to make you feel better.
我这周末带你去玩 你钓鱼吗
I feel fine.
I want to take you away this weekend.
Do you fish?
- 好了 现在就走了 - 我要上课!
(Andie sighs, class bell rings)
Okay, then we can go right now.
- 今晚吧 我不接受拒绝 - 请试一下
I have class.
Tonight at 7:00 and I won't take no for an answer.
这个女人的内心在受折磨 这就是全部的意义
Try, please.
This woman is suffering inside.
That's all there is to it.
伙计 下次我会踢你屁股 这次就这么算了
(banging loudly)
Yo, man, next time I'll kick your ass.
我是开玩笑而已
Dat'll be dat.
Dat'll-- I'm just kidding; that's-- it's a joke.
股市怎么样了
How about that stock market?
我的代理人是EF・休顿 他说…
My broker is E.F. Hutton, and E.F. Hutton says...
你看吧 没用的 我就说肯定没用
You see, it never works.
It never works.
I've never seen that work...
妈的!
(girls scream) DUCKIE: Oh, shit!
GIRL: What's going on out there?
Aah...
原来里面是这样的
So this is what it looks like.
真不错 稍等一下
This is great.
Hey, wait a minute, wai-w-w-w-wait.
你们的隔间是有门的 不会卡住
You got doors on the stalls, they're not stopped.
等等 男厕所就没有这些东西!
Wait a minute.
We don't have none of this stuff in the boys'--
wait a minute, we don't got none of this.
我们的隔间没有门…
We don't got doors on the stalls in the boys' room.
这是什么 我们也没有糖果机
We don't have-- what is this, what?
We don't have a candy machine in the boys' room.
- 什么都没有 - 是谁在叫
We don't got none of that. GIRL: I'm gonna start screaming
in a minute if you don't get out of here.
对不起 我现在要见校长了
I'm sorry, no, I want the principal here.
I want him here this instant.
就这样 我可以等 再见
I want-- now, this instant.
I'll wait.
Thank you.
妈的 为什么我做不来
Oh, shit!
Why can't I do this?
你做什么了 这… 你要先归零
What have you done?
This-- you have to subtotal first.
我每次都说 你每次都不听
I tell you this every time.
You never listen.
再来一曲 然后就去享受一段糟糕的恋爱
One more tune, then it's off to enjoy a terrible relationship.
邻家男孩就喜欢这个
(drops needle on record)
The furrier next door loves this.
? Soft words
? They are spoke so gentle, yeah ?
(loud knocking)
? It makes it easier
? Easier to bear
(shop bell rings)
(snaps fingers)
? You won't regret it, no, no ?
(mouthing words) ? Them young girls, they don't forget it ?
? Love
? Is their whole happiness
? Yeah
? But it's all so easy ?
? All you got to do is
? Try, try a little...
? Tenderness
? Yeah, oh, you got to do it, man ?
? Hold her where you want her
? Squeeze her, don't tease her ?
? Never leave her
? Give to her
? Got, got to try a little tenderness ?
? Yeah, yeah, yeah
? You got to know how to love her, man ?
? You've got to squeeze her, don't tease her ?
? Never leave
? You've got to hold her ?
? Rub her softly
? Try a little tenderness, yeah, yeah, yeah ?
? You got to rub her gently
? Don't bruise her, no, no ?
? You got to love her
? Tease her, don't displease her ?
? Got to try, now, now, now
? Try...
? Try a little tenderness
? Yeah...
? You got to know what to do, man ?
? Take this advice
? You got to love, squeeze, don't tease my baby ?
? Love her long...
(music fades out)
(breathing heavily)
女士们 这曲子很不错
(with accent): Evening, young ladies.
我妈妈以前会唱这歌 我爱奥蒂丝
This is a very good tune.
My mother used to sing this.
我们关门了
This is Otis; I love Otis.
- 知道年长的女人会怎么对我吗? - 给你换尿布?
We're closed.
You know what an older woman does for me?
爱抚? 你勉强算备选吧
Changes your diapers?
(without accent:) Touche.
但这是唐老鸭的爱情生活
No, seriously though, you're a very smoky alternative,
but this is the Duck Man's love in life.
- 可以吗 - 这样的?
Shall we?
You ever had one of these?
不要吧
I don't think so.
好了 我们锄大地吧!
Come on... let's plow.
我冒犯她们了
(with accent): Do I offend?
安迪
Andie, hon.
已经七点多了 不用浪费唇膏了
Listen, it's after 7:00.
- 我知道 罗娜 - 我不想泼你冷水
Don't waste good lip gloss.
I know, Iona.
I mean, I don't mean to be a bitch or anything,
但我觉得你今晚没有艳遇的
but I don't think
Mr. Wonderful is going to happen tonight.
我也不知道我在做什么
I don't know what I'm doing.
心怀妄想在化妆
Wishful makeupping.
等等 你们在用一种秘密的肢体语言交流
Come on.
Wait, wait.
You babes are, like, talking a sign language
而这里的唐老鸭完全不能理解
that the old Ducker here just does not understand.
介不介意指教一下 我都糊涂了
Now, would you mind filling me in here?
她被放鸽子了 傻子
I'm a little confused.
She got stood up, twerp.
放鸽子? 怎么回事 我在这儿呢!
Stood up?
Wait, h-how so? Wait, I'm here.
这是女性神秘协议还是什么?
I mean, is this like one of those feminine mystique deals
or something?
他来了
He showed.
Um...
安迪
Andie.
我来
I'll get that.
- 唐老鸭 真的对不起 - 这真的…
Duckie, I'm really sorry.
What, is this, um, you're gonna,
你要跟他出去? 这是什么 约会?
you're gonna go out with this guy?
I mean, is this, you know, like, a date, or something?
是的 你会喜欢他的
Yeah.
他真的跟别人不一样
I mean, you'll like him.
He's not like the other guys, seriously.
不 不可能 安迪!
No, n-no way, Andie!
你真气死我了 因为他们在侮辱每个人 包括你
You really piss me off, you know, 'cause,
'cause you know they shit all over everybody, including you.
- 我真不相信你会这么蠢 - 我不会让别人侮辱我的
I just-- I can't believe you'd be this stupid.
Who's shitting on me?
I'm not gonna let anybody shit on me.
他会把你玩过就甩掉 天哪 我可以为你去死!
He's just-- he's gonna use your ass and throw you away.
那我应该怎么办 他请我出去 而我喜欢他
God, I would have died for you.
So what am I supposed to do?
要是我知道他有钱就讨厌他
He asked me out and I like him.
If I hate him because he's got mon--
just listen to me-- if I hate him because he's got money,
跟他们讨厌我们没钱是一样的 明白吗
that's the exact same thing as them hating us because we don't.
你这么做就是不尊重自己
Do you understand?
You can't do this and, and respect yourself.
- 不能的 - 我来做决定 好吗
Y-You, you... you can't.
Well, I'll make that decision, all right?
当然 你想做什么都能做!
Sure, you c-- you can do what you want.
你这么说是因为我要跟布兰出去
You know, you're talking like that
just because I'm going out with Blane.
布兰? 他叫布兰?
Blane?
His, his name is Blane?
那是家电品牌 那不是名字!
Oh... that's a major appliance, that's not a name.
我跟布兰出去不代表我不能当你的朋友
Just because I'm going out with Blane doesn't mean
I can't be friends with you.
- 这不会改变我对你的感觉 - 你真贴心
I mean, it doesn't change the way I feel about you.
很高兴 重点是这个 安迪
Oh, that's very nice.
I'm, I'm glad.
Here's... here's the point, Andie.
我并不特别关心你喜不喜欢我
I'm n-- I'm not particularly concerned
with whether or not you like me.
因为我生来就喜欢你 我却不能再喜欢你了
'Cause I live to like you and, and,
and I can't like you anymore.
所以当你说你的心都碎了 你觉得卑下 肮脏
So, so when you get your heart splattered all over hell
and, and you're feeling really low and dirty,
别指望我能让你好起来 因为…
don't, don't look to me to help pump you back up,
'cause, 'cause, 'cause, 'cause maybe for the first time
因为也许在你生命中的第一次 我将不在场
in your life, I won't be there.
我不敢相信你说出这种话来
I can't believe you're actually saying this.
我猜这话就是不好听
Well, I guess that's just tough shit.
- 抱歉 - 抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
(loud thud)
- 店里那家伙… - 他是我朋友
That guy in the store.
我从小就认识他了 他是个好人
Oh, he was a friend of mine.
I've known him since I was a kid.
- 是吗 - 是的 我很喜欢他
He's a really nice guy. Yeah?
Yeah, I like him a lot.
想回家换衣服吗
So you want to go home and change?
已经换了
(laughs quietly)
I already did.
- 抱歉 - 没关系
(laughs quietly)
Sorry. No, that's okay.
Oh, boy.
我们要去哪儿
So, where are we going?
你要去派对?
You up for a party?
是的 不 也许?
Yeah? No? Maybe?
我不想去
No, I don't think so.
- 为什么 - 为什么
Why? "Why?"
- 他们是我朋友 没关系 - 是你的朋友
Come on, they're my friends, it's okay.
直到我认为他们接受了你 否则我不会走的
That's it; they're your friends.
I wouldn't take you
if I didn't think they'd accept you.
我们不能去别的地方吗
Can't we just go somewhere else?
安迪 我喜欢你 我觉得你也喜欢我
Hey, Andie, I like you.
我知道有闲言碎语 但如果你不介意我也一样
I think you like me.
I mean, we both know there's a lot of bullshit that goes on,
but if you're above it, I'm above it.
如果我们想有所发展 我们就要应对 是不是
If we want to make anything out of this whatever,
we got to deal with it, right?
- 是的 - 好了 我跟你一样可能有所损失
Yeah.
Come on, I got as much to lose as you.
如果你想 我们可以跟你的朋友出去 我们可以不问世事
We can go out with your friends if you want.
Go crawl under a rock.
只要你想 你来做决定
Anything you want.
- 我们可以去滑翔 - 我没有滑翔过
The choice is yours.
We can go hang gliding. You like hang gliding?
凡事都有第一次
I've never been hang gliding.
Well, first for everything.
要是不好玩 我们就走
If it's a bad time, we leave.
(thunder rumbling)
?
MAN (faintly): It's time for more beer!
- 嗨 布兰 - 艾迪
Hi, Blane. Hey, Eddie.
Hey, see you later.
(music playing, partyers laughing and chatting)
Hey, what's up, bro?
你是不是艺术课上那女孩?
Hey, aren't you the girl in my art class?
珍珠很漂亮 这不是晚宴 宝贝
Nice pearls.
This isn't a dinner party, honey.
小心
Watch it.
- 嘿 布兰 你好吗 - 嘿 凯文
Hey, Blane, how you doing?
Hey, Kev, what's up?
? So I keep believing
? That you and I can change the world ?
? I'm going 'round and 'round, 'round again ?
? I say things that I really shouldn't say ?
? I'm going 'round, 'round again ?
真不敢相信我跟他们是朋友
I can't believe I actually associate with these people.
我不敢相信我真来了
I can't believe that I'm actually here.
- 够糟的是吧? - 是够糟的
Pretty bad, huh?
Yeah, it's pretty bad.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我们上楼吧
Hey, let's go upstairs,
huh?
好了
Look, I didn't come here to get you off, okay?
我不是为了赚你便宜 我没有这个心
That was not my idea.
我不是这个意思 我还没亲你呢 是不是
Andie.
Come on, that is not what I meant.
I haven't even tried to kiss you, have I?
这边安静一点 好不
Look, it's quieter up there, okay?
来吧 我的手会放在口袋里 我保证
Come on.
These hands will remain in these pockets, I swear to God.
这样好了吧 我毫无防御能力
Look at me here.
Come on.
而且傻的冒泡
I'm utterly defenseless.
And utterly foolish.
Come on.
- 你觉得这地毯怎么样 - 很漂亮
So what do you think of these carpets, huh?
Utterly fab.
肯定好玩的
It's going to be good.
- 嘿 布兰 - 什泰夫
Oh, hey, Blane.
- 你好吗 - 很好
Steff. How're you doing?
- 我再找间房 - 不用 进来吧
All right... no, I'll get another room.
No, no, no, no, come on in. I'm watching some tunes here.
我正看卡通呢
So... who you got with you here, Blane?
你跟谁一起来的 布兰?
Uh, Andie, this is Steff; Steff, Andie.
安迪 这是什泰夫 什泰夫 这是安迪
很高兴见到你 安迪
Oh, it's very nice to meet you, Andie.
你是想过来坐下还是上床?
Ah, listen, uh, you want to come in and s-sit down?
不用 我们不用
Or you want the bed, is that it? No, no.
过来喝一杯 想来点什么
We're fine. At least come in and have a drink.
这是我高中生涯里最后一场重大的派对
Let's go. Can I get you something?
I mean, this is my last serious party of my high school career.
希望你们能挺到周日 那时我家就没人了
I hope you guys are gonna tough it out until Sunday,
我觉得这个会杀了那个狗娘养的 布兰
at least when my folks get home.
I think this one may just finally kill the old
离童贞又远了一大步
son of a bitch, Blane.
Another giant step away
你是个婊子 是不是 本尼?
from virginity I went.
You are a slut, aren't you, Benny?
天哪
(sighs): Oh, my God.
- 我做恶梦了? - 我们有客人了
Am I having a nightmare? We've got guests.
我认识你 你跟我一起上数学课
BENNY: I know you.
You're in my calculus class.
- 体育课 - 你叫体育课?
Gym.
你真没用 是不是
Your name's Jim?
You are worthless, aren't you?
你和你朋友那天对我可不怎么友好
You and your friends gave me a lot of shit the other day. Everybody gives you shit.
- 放轻松 本尼, - 这是什泰夫的派对 布兰
Take it easy, Benny, huh?
This is Steff's party, Blane.
- 不用告诉我该做什么 - 什泰夫…
Don't tell me what to do.
你不能随便带什么人来
Steff.
I mean, you shouldn't be allowed to invite just anybody.
什泰夫 她搞坏了气氛
Steff, she's going to ruin my night.
- 闭嘴 本尼 - 你是基 布兰
Shut up, Benny!
You're a faggot, Blane.
好吧 听着 本尼
All right, okay, listen, Benny...
- 我们还是… - 你要去哪儿
- 我们把房间让给他们 - 为什么
Why don't we just... Where are you going?
Let's just leave them with the room, okay? Why?
- …我们去找点吃的 - 你知道我喜欢什么
And we will get you something to eat, all right.
肋骨吧
Oh, you've got what I want.
Some ribs, or something.
你们先玩吧 等会儿见
Listen, you guys, enjoy yourselves, and, uh...
we'll see you later, maybe.
我怀疑
BENNY: I doubt it.
- 还好吗 - 没事
STEFF: You all right?
你是个混蛋 我以前还不知道呢
Fine. You're an asshole. All right.
我带她去别处发疯 自己玩吧 布兰
I don't want to know what you are.
I'm gonna take her to throw up somewhere. Listen, enjoy yourself.
他们一喝酒就这样 坏主意
They're kind of jerks when they drink, huh?
现在能带我走了吗
Bad idea.
Can you just get me out of here now?
好的
Yeah.
我不想送你回家 我想跟你在一起
Look, I don't want to take you home.
如果这里不好就换别处 只要你想
I mean, I'd like to be with you.
If not here, somewhere else; anywhere you want.
对不起 我能说什么呢 我犯了个错
I'm sorry.
What can I say? I made a mistake.
我高估了我的朋友 抱歉
I overestimated my friends.
I'm sorry.
- 你想打我吗 - 是的
What, you want to hit me?
Yes, I do.
请吧
Be my guest.
(indistinct chatter, laughter)
(The Rave-Ups "Rave-up/Shut-up" begins)
? Grow up
? My good beliefs say to me, stand up ?
? Like a real man is supposed to be, rave up ?
? Rest of all your fantasies, rave up ?
想知道我的事?
? It's just a dream... ?
You want to know my thing?
要是我真心喜欢一个女孩
If I really have it solid for a girl,
我会骑车到她家
I'll ride by her house on my bike.
我会一天去一百次
I'll do it like... like a hundred times in a day.
这真是… 太强了
It's really-- it's intense.
你停车吗
You ever park?
我是那种开车驶过的人
I'm kind of a drive-by kind of guy.
? Rave up
? 'Cause being down ain't being a rat's head up ?
? So fool those rats another time, rave up... ?
要喝一杯吗
You want a drink? Yeah.
- 好的! - 好?
Yeah? Coke.
- 可乐 - 可乐? 好
Coke? Coke, okay.
告诉我你住在哪儿 我就到你那去
Give me your address.
I'll, I'll put you on my route.
好吧 你得帮我一把
Okay, you're gonna have to help me out here.
有一天那女孩会知道她错过了什么
You know, you know, someday that girl's going to realize just what she missed.
别停下 再来!
Come on, don't stop, give me more!
Yeah!
- 嗨! - 嗨
Hi! IONA: Hi!
- 白马痞子出去了? - 不 他在吧台
Prince Charming whimp out?
No, no, he's at the bar.
唐老鸭
Duckie?
他不高兴
(yawns)
他不想再骑车经过你家了
He's sulking.
He's not gonna ride his bike past your house anymore.
唐老鸭 你真是个大混蛋
Duckie, you're being
a real jerk.
他是怎么进来的
How'd he get in here anyway?
- 我说他是我孩子 - 你怎么会来
I said he was my kid.
How come you're here?
我整晚都在研究这问题呢
I've been trying to figure that all night.
? You lost a lot when you lost me ?
- 抱歉 - 妈妈给你做的?
Sorry. Mom make this for you?
乱乱的哈
Yeah. Gross, huh?
不好意思
? You lost a lot when you lost me ?
? Six paperback books and a dime tree ?
? You lost a lot when you lost me, six paperback books... ?
- 嗨 - 过来
Hi. Hi.
- 你见过罗娜了 是不是 - 没正式见过 嗨 我是布兰
Here you go.
Thanks. You met Iona, didn't you?
戴眼镜的是杜基・戴尔
Not formally. Hi, Blane.
And, um, that's Duckie Dale over there behind the glasses.
- 嗨 唐老鸭 - 菲利浦・F・戴尔 去死
Hi, Duckie.
Philip F. Dale to you, scum wad.
你们到底是去哪儿了
So where you guys been?
- 我有个朋友开了派对 - 真不错!
Oh, a friend of mine was having a party.
Oh, how adorable.
- 是的 有点不爽 - 你去了一个不爽的派对?
Yeah, it was a little intense.
DUCKIE: Oh, wait, wait, you had an intense party?
- 不 是我一个朋友开的 - 唐老鸭 闭嘴
No, it was a friend of mine's, I said.
Duckie... shut up!
- 有什么问题 - 这是一首古典作品
What's the problem?
This is a classic, classic piece of work here.
- 唐老鸭 好了! - 菲尔
Duckie, please... Phil.
菲尔 我觉得你让安迪不自在了 快算了吧
BLANE: Hey, Phil, I think you're making Andie uncomfortable.
Why don't you just knock it off? What's the problem?
我把一生都奉献给了她 他却冲上来自认为了解她
I devoted my life to the girl, and this guy, he comes
in one day and-and-and thinks he knows her, that's funny.
你可以打电话给大卫・莱特曼 他一分钟就可以给你订上
You should give David Letterman a ring sometime.
菲尔 你想让我们走吗
I'm sure he'd book you in a minute.
是的 非常感谢
Phil, would you like us to leave?
You know, that's very perceptive.
好
Come on.
看看他的礼数 真是礼貌!
(laughing): And look at the manners on this guy; this was a treat.
你只是个小孩子
Really, thanks a million. You're a great couple of kids, really.
今晚我竟然还为你难过 你个蠢蛋侏儒!
You know, I can't believe I actually felt bad for you tonight,
retarded, little dwarf.
再见
See you.
很高兴见到你 再见
Nice meeting you.
- 抱歉 - 没关系
See you later.
- 没关系 - 混蛋
Sorry. No problem.
(mockingly): No problem.
说吧 大傻逼 从你嘴里说出来我觉得是恭维呢
You're an asshole.
Hey, blow me, butt wad.
Coming from you, I take it as a compliment.
安迪!
Andie! Yo!
你被换掉了
You been replaced.
对不起
Gee, I'm... I'm sorry.
(electric guitar instrumental break)
现在要干啥
Well, what now?
我要早起 今晚就算了吧
I gotta get up early.
Why don't we just forget it.
干吗 回家?
What, home?
- 想去我家吗 - 不了 谢谢
Hey, you want to go to my house?
No, thanks.
- 想吃东西吗 - 不想
You want to eat?
你想做什么吗
No.
What do you want to do?
Anything.
你送我到泰克丝吧
Um... why don't you just drop me off at Trax.
- 泰克丝? - 这里离我家很近的
You know, I can, I can... Trax?
It's real close to where I live.
- 太晚了 我送你回去 - 我有些东西还要做完
Well, it's late; I'll just drop you home.
You want to go home, I'll drop you home.
No, but I have something I have to do there.
现在? 很晚了 你想回家我就送你回去
Now? Come on, it's late.
You want to go home, I'll drop you home, it's fine.
- 我不想你送我回家 - 好吧 那就出去 你想去哪儿
I don't want you to take me home.
Okay, let's go out.
No, I don't want... We'll go out, anywhere you want,
- 我不想出去 - 你也不想回家
anything you want to do. I don't want to go out.
- 你想做什么 - 我不想你送我回家
You don't want to go out, you don't want to go home.
What do you want to do, Andie?
I don't want you to take me home.
我有些东西弄不明白…
Wait, I'm missing something. I'm not a jerk here.
I don't understand what you're saying. Wait a minute.
- 等等 不要走开 - 别 我只是不想…
Let's go. Don't walk away. Wait a minute. I'm talking to you.
- 你不明白吗 - 我不明白
No. Just please, I just don't want you... Why?
听着 我不想你送我回家
Don't you understand me?! No, I don't... at all.
Will you listen to me?
好的 你是怎么了
I don't want you to take me home. Okay, why?
因为我不想你知道我住在什么地方
What is the problem?
Because I don't want you to see where I live, okay?
- 什么 - 对不起 当我没说
What?
I'm sorry, forget it.
It's okay.
天哪
(sotto voce): Jesus Christ.
(keys jangling)
(car starts)
(crickets chirping)
抱歉我毁了你的夜晚
(dogs barking in distance)
I'm really sorry for bumming out the night for you.
你没毁坏什么 我过得很开心
You didn't bum out anything, I had a great time.
- 骗子 - 我跟你在一起很开心
You liar.
I was with you. I had a great time.
要是我在土耳其的监狱 要是有你 我还会开心的
If I was in a Turkish prison, I'd have a great time with you.
不知道 这对我来说太怪了 也许这样是不对的
I don't know, it's just...
It's too weird for me, you know? Maybe this shouldn't happen.
哪样 你和我?
What, you and me?
也许不会一直这样 但并不意味着这样就是错的
Well, you know, maybe it doesn't happen all the time,
it doesn't mean it isn't right. Right?
并不意味着我们不能试试
Doesn't mean you can't try.
我请你去毕业舞会能不能感觉好一点
Would you feel any better if I asked you to the prom?
我知道毕业舞会挺傻的 所以要是你不想去也没什么…
I mean, I know the prom's kind of lame,
so if you don't want to go, it's really no big deal.
(door squeaking)
嘿 怎么了
(screams)
Hey. What?
成了 他邀请我了
It happened!
- 还有呢? - 我接受了
He asked me.
And?
祝贺你
I accepted!
不用再蹦着跳着等电话了
Well, congratulations.
No more moping around
the house waiting for the telephone to ring?
怎么 你恋爱了?
So... you in love?
- 我觉得是吧 - 对方是谁
Yeah, I think I am.
Well, who is this guy?
他叫布兰 是毕业班的 他好帅
His name is Blane.
And he's a senior, he's so beautiful.
是个富二代
(both chuckle)
Um, he's a... richie.
- 啥代? - 富二代 这真蠢
A whatie?
A richie, it's kind of stupid.
就是他家挺有钱的
It's just his family has a lot of money.
- 这有问题吗 - 不知道 就是感觉很怪
Oh, well, is that a problem?
I don't know, it's just weird.
他的朋友很有钱 他也有钱
You know, his friends have a lot of money,
他开宝马
and he has a lot of money.
He drives a BMW.
我就是… 不知道… 我不知道他能不能接受我
I don't know, I'm not really sure if they're gonna accept me.
Well, what does that mean?
这什么意思 你们互相喜欢
I mean, you like him, he likes you.
他朋友怎么想根本不重要
What his friends think shouldn't make any difference.
是的 但我的朋友也这样 大家都这样
Yeah, but it's not just his friends, it's my friends, too.
我觉得没有安全感
It's everybody. I'm just not real... secure about it.
抓紧享受
Well, so take the heat.
你喜欢他 他喜欢你 这就值了
I mean, you like him, he likes you; it's worth it.
- 是吗 - 难道不是吗
Is it?
Well, isn't it?
你说的对
You're right.
- 我是过虑了 对吧 - 不必这样的
I'm just overreacting, aren't I?
深情的一吻能扰乱任何人的内心
Oh, not necessarily.
I mean, a good kiss can scramble
anybody's brain.
不用担心 明天看看会是怎样
Look, just don't worry about it, you know?
And wait and see how you feel tomorrow.
- 晚安 - 晚安 谢谢
Good night, hon.
Good night. Thanks.
这才是我的宝贝
That's my baby.
亲爱的
Uh, honey.
等一下 我问你点事
Uh, would you-- wait a minute.
好的
Could-could I ask you something?
Yeah.
有时我觉得有点抱歉
Uh... sometimes I feel a little sorry
这样的事情你得跟我说
that, um, I'm the one you have to talk to about these things.
我没觉得 别人说的也没你好
I'm not.
She couldn't have said it any better than you.
- 我是说真的 - 晚安
I mean it.
Good night.
(mid-tempo rock beat playing)
好的 来丰富我吧
Okay, make my day.
我要听所有的细节
I want all the gory details.
交融的呼吸 跳动的内心 潮湿的窗户
The mingling breath,
the pounding heart, the steamy windows.
全部对我说
I want the whole scoop.
我不想让你失望 但什么都没发生
Well, I hate to disappoint you,
but nothing happened.
闹太套?
Nothing?
也不是完全没有 我吻了他
Well, not nothing, I mean, I kissed him.
- 有劲爆的吗 - 好了
Anywhere interesting?
Oh, please.
所以…
So...
他的嘴唇有力吗
uh...
does he have strong lips?
- 这要怎么判断 - 你的膝盖感觉到了吗
How can you tell?
Do you feel it in your knees?
- 我全身都感觉到了 - 给力的嘴唇
I felt it everywhere.
Strong lips.
说说嘴唇!
(Iona laughs)
Talk about lips.
我老的可以当他妈 但当唐老鸭亲我时
(laughing)
I mean, I'm old enough to be his mother,
but when the Duck laid
我发誓 我全身都被烧灼了
that kiss on me last night,
I swear
to God, my thighs just went up in flames.
他肯定是在甜瓜上练习过了
He must practice on melons, or something.
这是你的舞会礼服?
This your prom dress?
(laughs)
- 信不信随你 - 真好看
Believe it or not.
It's great.
- 好傻 - 面料很好
It's silly.
It's great material.
要知道 我要去
You know, I'm going...
去毕业舞会
to prom.
- 好了! - 不 我要去
Stop it!
(giggling): Well, I am.
昨晚他问我了 我也不知道 我答应了
Last night he asked me.
And I don't know, I said yes.
真的好怪啊
It's really weird.
但可能挺好玩的
But it might be kind of fun.
你来了15分钟了 现在才告诉我
IONA: You were here for 15 minutes
and you didn't even tell me!
我真的非常想去
ANDIE: Oh, but I really, really wanted to go.
(giggles)
你真走运
You lucky girl.
? Cherish is the word I use to describe... ?
这就是梦幻礼服?
Isn't that a dreamy dress?
? All the feeling
? That I have hiding here for you inside ?
? You don't know how many times I've wished ?
? That I had told you
- 罗娜 我得走了 - 在这首歌唱完之前拉住我好吗
? That I could hold you...
Iona, I have to go.
Can you just hold till this song is over?
但我得走了
But I have to leave.
我们能不能返老还童一点
Oh, why can't we start old and get younger?
我嫉妒你 我嫉妒死你了!
? Cherish is the word...
I envy you.
I really envy you!
罗娜 你怀旧过度了
Iona, you're gonna O.D. on nostalgia.
我喜欢《山水又相逢》
I loved "The Big Chill".
- 我爱这条裙子 - 真漂亮
I love this dress.
是的
It's a great dress.
我妈给我买的 她非常开心
Yeah.
My mother bought it for me.
God, she was so happy.
我看起来正常 这是第一次也是最后一次
It was the first
and last time I ever looked normal.
我是指相对来说
I mean, you know, relatively speaking.
要是我的约会对像不是唯一一个可以钓到的 俩孩子的爸
It would have been a fairy tale
if my date hadn't been the only one at the prom
那就完美了
with a...
wife and two kids.
想试试吗 你穿上一定好看
You want to try it on?
I bet it'd look great on you.
你的屁股比我年轻15岁
I mean, your butt is 15 years younger than mine.
我以前也有翘臀 我爱我的屁股 真希望当时拍照留念了
I mean, I used to have a great butt.
I did!
I loved my butt!
- 想试试这件吗 - 不了 等等吧
I wish I had photographs of it.
You want to try this on?
你要走了 我知道 我自己准备好
Mm, nah, not right now.
Oh, yeah, you gotta go, I know.
I know.
- 你要出去? - 是的 新人
I gotta get ready myself.
You're going out? Yeah.
New guy.
特伦丝 开宠物店的
Terrance, he owns a pet shop.
看看进展如何
We'll see what happens.
- 帮我挤白马王子一下 - 我会的
(giggles)
Have fun.
Give Mr. Perfecto a squeeze
for me. Oh, I will.
听着
Hey, listen, uh,
要是见到你的小唐老鸭 对他好一点
if you see your little Duck Man...
他受伤不轻
be kind.
He's nursing some fairly serious wounds.
- 好吗 - 好
Okay?
Okay.
- 拜拜 - 拜
Bye-bye.
Bye.
我们去吃寿司
Hey, you know, we're going for, uh, sushi.
你觉得这样太过分了?
Do you think this is too much?
再见
Bye.
? You don't know how many times I've wished that I... ?
我觉得你昨晚非常不好
Thought that was very uncool of you
- 什么? - "什么"!
last night, Blane. What?
- 你是指安迪? - 我就是指安迪
What?
You mean Andie?
怎么了 我喜欢她
Yeah, I mean Andie.
What's the big deal, I like her.
说实话 我有点生气你们对她不友好
As a matter of fact,
I was pissed off at you guys for being so nasty
你私自带她来派对 这样不好
to her. It was way out of order
for you to foist her on the party.
什泰夫 你听到你说的话了 你说的是我听到的屁话吗
Steff, do you hear yourself?
You hear the same asshole shit I hear?
- 我还得给你讲清楚吗 布兰? - 是吧
What, do I have to spell it out for you, Blane?
没人欣赏你的幽默感
I guess so.
Nobody appreciates your sense of humor, you know.
事实上 大家都恶心的要命
As a matter of fact, everybody is just about to puke from it.
要是你喜欢垃圾 别带到我们面前来 行吗 伙计
You know, if you've got a hard-on
for trash, don't take care of it
好的 兄弟
around us, pal, all right?
Right, buddy.
我这次真的不要过度 布兰 真的不用
Listen,
I don't need a lot of shit on this one, Blane,
all right? I really don't.
Money all that matters to you?
- 钱就是你关心的一切? - 这话从何说起?
Wh-Where in the hell does that come from?
你看看 要是我缺钱 我还能把我爹妈的房子弄成这样?
Well, look around you, would I treat my parents house like this
if I, if money was any
为什么要这样 直接推倒完事
kind of issue?
Well, wh-why are you doing this?
You know, why don't you just nail her
- 怎么还投入感情了? - 这样有什么问题?
and get it over with.
You know, why are you getting involved?
我就是觉得这样很蠢 没意义
Is there something wrong with that?
I just think it's stupid.
- 我觉得你父母会很高兴的 - 他们跟此事无关
You know, it's pointless.
you know, and your parents,
I think they'll be thrilled.
They have nothing to do with it.
我看到你妈对你的期望了 布兰 这很不好
Really? Yeah.
I've seen your mother go to work on you, Blane.
等比尔和乔易斯跟你练完
You know, it's vicious!
And when Bill and Joyce get through with you,
你就不知道是什么下场了
you won't know whether to shit
or go sailing.
这谈话无聊透了 布兰
Listen, I, I'm getting really bored with this conversation.
要是你想找个低等小妞玩玩 没问题
All right, Blane.
You know, if you want your little piece of low-grade ass,
但要是你这么做了 你就没朋友了
fine, take it,
you know, but if you do,
- 是这样吗 - 是这样的
you're not gonna have a friend.
Is that right?
Yeah, that's right.
要是你想做选择 选吧
I mean, if you want to make the choice,
go ahead and make it, all right?
我个人是不会据此而断绝友谊的 但我很老派 所以…
I, I personally wouldn't trash a friendship over it,
but... hey, I'm old-fashioned.
洗个澡吧 你丑死了
So...
Why don't you take a shower; you look like shit.
要是两星期前 有人说我会跟你出去
ANDIE: Two weeks ago,
if somebody told me
我肯定不会相信的
that I'd be going out with you,
I never would have believed them.
- 为什么 我没那么坏 - 是的 但是…
BLANE: Why?
I'm not all that bad.
我跟你呢?
No, but...
What about me and you?
你没见过或交谈过的人会成为你的敌人 简直是有病
You know, it's so insane
that somebody you've never met,
never talked to can be your enemy.
Mm... yeah.
是的
那你不该见我的父母
You shouldn't meet my parents, then.
好的
(laughs)
Okay.
他们也不是魔鬼 不过…
Well, I mean, they're not ogres, but...
(both laugh)
我觉得他们还是喜欢包办婚姻
I think they still believe in arranged marriages.
企业家族代替皇室家族
Corporate families replaced royal families.
我是多诺电气的加冕王子
I'm the crowned prince of McDonnough Electric.
- 跑题了 - 没有
It's irrelevant.
No.
是的
Yeah.
- 我想让他们去死 - 那就让他们去死
I could just tell them all to go to hell.
- 大家都是 朋友们 父母 - 每一个人
Tell them to go to hell.
Everyone, friends, parents.
All of them. All of them.
你呢
What about you?
要是别人不信我 那我也不信他
Hmm?
Somebody doesn't believe in me, I...
I can't believe in them.
你不撒谎 是不是
You don't lie, do you?
我不必撒谎
I don't have to lie.
总会发生的
This is gonna happen.
我很希望能发生
Okay, I really want this to happen.
是的
Yeah.
(distant train passing)
? So, please, please, please
? Let me, let me, let me
? Let me get what I want...
- 能帮你吗 - 我很好 谢谢
Can I help you?
- 毕业舞会的东西 - 随便看看
I'm fine, thank you.
Something for the prom?
要是你有什么需要…
Just looking.
Yeah, well, if you need anything, uh...
- 真难看 - 非常合适
(sighs)
This is trash.
MOTHER: It's very becoming.
妈妈 看着像是我站在结婚蛋糕上似的
Mother, it looks
like I should be standing on top of a wedding cake.
宝贝 好了
Oh, darling, don't I wish.
我讨厌这面料 还有 我最受不了浅蓝色
And I hate this material
and by the way, I cannot stand baby blue.
(phone rings)
(phone continues ringing)
- 知道他在哪儿吗 - 对不起 他没告诉我
Well, do you know where he is?
WOMAN: No, I'm sorry,
he didn't tell me where he was going.
要是他打电话或是回家来 让他联系我好吗
Okay, well, then if he calls or comes home
- 你是谁 - 安迪
can you just tell him to call me?
- 谁 - 安迪
Who is this, please? Andie.
- 好吧 能留下号码吗 - 他知道
Who? Andie!
Well, yes, could I have your number?
- 好吧 我给他写个条 宝贝 - 好的 谢了 再见
Yeah, no, he has the number.
Well, fine, I'll leave him a note, dear.
Okay, thanks. Bye.
他到底在哪儿
(sighs)
Where in the hell is he?
(dog panting)
(sighs)
不要爱上一个人 你不会喜欢的
Never fall in love, Ace, you just won't like it.
这很复杂
It's very complicated.
安迪!
Andie?
Andie!
- 安迪! - 进来
(knocking on door) Andie.
Come in.
- 嗨 - 嗨 老爸
Hi. Hi, Daddy.
我有东西给你
I brought you something.
- 是什么 - 我给你买的一点小东西
What is it?
Well, it's a little something I picked up
for you.
? Ta-tah.
有点旧 但我知道要是你有心 可以做出很美的东西来
I know it's a little busy,
but I know you can make something out of it.
If you need to.
- 喜欢吗 - 这颜色真漂亮
Wow. Yeah.
Do you like it?
It's a beautiful color.
Yeah. It's really pretty.
天哪 让我想到了你妈妈
God, it reminds me so much of your mom.
她最爱粉红色 她穿粉色特别漂亮
You know, she always wore pink.
And she looked
- 挺好的 谢谢 - 好的
so beautiful in it.
It's okay.
Okay. Thank you.
Okay.
- 爸爸 - 怎么
Daddy.
What?
我想让你知道我真的很喜欢
I just want you to know I really appreciate this.
我觉得我可以做点东西出来
I think I can make something out of it.
- 我能问个问题吗 - 可以 说吧
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
What?
你从哪弄的钱买这个
Where'd you get the money to pay for this?
不贵的 我也有些钱
Well, why, it wasn't that much.
- 新工作赚的? - 是的 新工作
I had some money.
From your new job?
Ah, yeah, from my new job.
我周三上班前回过家 你的车还在
(sighs)
I came home before work on Wednesday
and your car was in the driveway.
Mm-hmm.
- 你不必骗我的 - 不
You know, you didn't have to lie to me.
- 你不必的! - 就是 我没去面试
Yes, I did. No, you didn't.
Yes, I did. I had a line on something
- 为什么不去 - 忘了
and I missed the appointment.
Oh, why'd you miss the appointment?
不是这样的 你根本不想工作
It slipped my mind.
It didn't slip your mind.
你去见顾问是因为那是他们让你去的
You didn't want the job.
You just went to the counselor because I forced you to.
- 你想说什么 安迪? - 我想说你只是没去而已
Am I right? Yeah, what's your point, Andie?!
My point is, you just didn't go!
- 我故意不去面试? - 是的
You saying I deliberately missed
the appointment? Yes.
你就这么想我?
Is this how you feel about me?
是的
(sighs)
Yes.
- 我本来还不知道 - 现在你知道了
Well, I didn't know this.
Well, now you do.
你现在知道了一切是吧 你18岁还有奖学金
Oh, you know everything, now, huh?
You're 18
and you got a scholarship
- 这不公平 - 我很笨 给不了你任何东西
and, uh, you're, uh, That's not fair!
all grown-up and free,
and I'm just an ignorant son of a bitch who never
- 我没要求过什么! - 太有才了
gave you anything. Hey, I never asked
你为什么不能忘了她?
Oh, that's brilliant!
Why can't you just forget her?!
- 你上学要迟到了 - 不 别走开
It's late; you got school.
- 你听我说完好吗 - 我已经听够了
No, don't walk out on this!
Will you please just
listen to me?! Please?!
是的 你每天都这么想
I've already been through this, Andie!
Sure, you go through it every day!
你为什么认不清呢 她已经走了 永远也不会回来了
You're still going through it!
Why can't you just realize that she's gone
and she's not gonna come back?!
- 她永远也不会回来了! - 闭嘴!
She's never coming back!
你为什么不接受现实 她走了 她…
Shut up! Dad...
Goddamn it! why can't you accept it?!
She's just gone!
你为什么不接受?
She...
Why can't you accept it?
因为…
Because... I love her.
我爱她 这就是原因
That's why.
我也爱她 你知道的
Well, I loved her, too, you know.
(crying)
但她就是不爱我们
She just didn't love us back.
(sighs)
她试过了 我也不知道 她就是不能爱我们
Okay, she tried.
I don't know.
She just couldn't handle it.
是的 但我知道 我一直都知道
Yeah, but I... I-I knew it.
我五岁时就感觉到了
I knew it all along.
I mean, when I was five, I felt it.
还记得她那次没回家吗?
Remember when she didn't come home that time?
我当时就知道了 我知道原因 我14岁时就知道了
I knew it then, I knew why.
你都50了 可还是不知道
I was 14, and I knew it.
You were 50, and you didn't.
要知道 你不能老是活在回忆里
You know, you can't go on living every day in the past.
她抛下了我们 不是我们抛弃的她 我们也无能为力
She left us, Daddy. We didn't leave her.
There was nothing we could do about it.
It just happened.
(sighs)
女儿啥时候比老爸知道的还多了?
Since when is the daughter supposed
to know more than her father?
(chuckles)
我就是个傻逼
(sniffles)
I've just been a blind fool.
你是个要刮胡子的傻逼
(sighs)
And you're a blind fool that needs a shave, too.
我是得刮胡子了
And I need a shave.
呃…
(sighs heavily)
Well...
你上床睡觉吧 明天要上学
(sighs)
You'd better get to bed.
我也得休息 明天我也有事要做
You got school.
And I got to hit the hay, too,
'cause I got a few things that I got to do tomorrow.
好的
Okay?
Okay.
我应该可以给你搞双鞋 但我不知道你穿几号
Uh, I would have got you some shoes,
but I didn't know your size.
(door closes)
(crying)
(sniffles and sighs)
?
(class bell rings)
嘿 玛丽
How you doing?
(indistinct crowd chatter)
- 你好吗 - 你怎么不给我打电话
How you doing?
Why haven't you called me?
我的平衡有点问题 马夫看到我们了 这违反俱乐部规则
Oh, I got nailed for the stable thing.
I guess a groom saw us. It's against club rules.
我给你打了三次电话 还给你留言了
I called you three times, and I left messages.
是吗 我没收到
Yeah?
Well, I-I didn't get them. My family,
我的家人对此没有责任
they're very irresponsible about that stuff, you know?
我今早等你了
I waited for you this morning.
- 是吗 在哪儿 - 停车场
Yeah? Where?
Parking lot.
我看到你了 我以为你也看到了我
I saw you, and I thought that you saw me.
没有
No.
怎么回事 布兰?
What about prom, Blane?
(sighs)
我今天不舒服 晚点谈好吗
Oh, Andie, I'm having a bad day. Can we talk later?
- 不行 毕业舞会怎么办 - 放学后见吧
No. What about prom? Come on.
- 不 舞会怎么办? - 安迪 好了
Why don't we just meet after school?
No! What about prom?!
- 说吧 - 说什么
Andie, come on.
Just say it. What?
我要听你说
Just say it! I want to hear you
- 安迪 别这样行吗 - 我要听你说
say it.
BLANE: Andie, please, all right?
I want to hear you say it.
一个月前 我邀请了别人却忘了
A month ago, I asked somebody else,
你是个骗子 你是个无耻的大骗子!
and I forgot. You're a liar!
You're a filthy, fucking, no-good liar!
你根本没胆告诉我真话
You don't have the guts to tell me the truth!
- 你说吧! - 我没撒谎
Just say it! I'm not lying.
- 告诉! - 你到底想听什么
Tell me! What?
Tell me! What do you want to hear?!
Just tell me! What?!
- 你觉得跟我在一起很羞耻 - 不 我不害羞
You're ashamed to be seen with me!
你害怕 你怕你的富朋友们不同意!
No, I am not, I am not!
You're ashamed to go out with me!
You're afraid. No, I'm...
You're terrified your Goddamn rich friends won't approve!
就说真话吧!
Just say it!
Just tell me the truth!
(exhales deeply)
你不明白这事跟你一点关系也没有
You don't understand it.
It has nothing at all
to do with you.
安迪!
Andie!
(footsteps running)
安迪!
Andie?
算了吧 根本不值得伤心
Forget about it, man.
It's not worth getting upset over it, you know?
- 为什么不脱下来? - 所有对我这样的女孩
BLANE: Ah, why don't you just take off, Steff, please?
我都不必抓着不放 布兰
Well, listen, any girl that did that to me,
I would not be too jazzed
to hold on to, Blane.
不值得 我告诉过你行不通的
It's not worth it, man.
I told you, it wasn't gonna work, you know.
以前 现在和以后的女孩 都一样
The girl was, is and will always be nada.
(door opening)
(footsteps thudding on stairs)
有问题吗 朋友?
You got a problem, friend?
(scoffs)
(Duckie yelling)
(grunting and groaning)
(coughing)
(grunts)
Come on.
(blows landing)
(grunting)
没事 没事
All right, all right!
谢谢
Nice, huh?
? She was a showgirl (gong-sounding doorbell chimes)
? With yellow feathers in her hair ?
? And a dress cut down to there ? (gong chimes)
? She would merengue
IONA: ? And do the cha-cha
- 安迪? - 是的
IONA: Cha-cha! Andie?
? And while she tried to be a star... ?
- 你是安迪 是不是 - 我是
Yeah? You're Andie, aren't you?
- 你怎么认识我 - 罗娜告诉我的 我是特伦丝
Yeah, I am.
Uh, how do you know me?
Well, Iona told me.
I'm Terrance. Terry.
- 宠物店的是不是 - 是的 之类之类的
? They were young and they had each other... ?
Oh, the pet shop, right?
她在卧室准备呢 你最好去告诉她时间不多了
Yeah, among other things.
She's in the bedroom getting ready.
You might want to go in there and tell her
好的
to shake her tail feather; we're late.
Okay.
? At the Copa, Copacabana
罗娜?
Iona?
? Music and passion were always the fashion ?
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
? At the Copa
? They fell in love
? Copa ?
IONA: ? Copa
? Cabana, a yellow feather
? She was a show girl
- 罗娜? - 亲爱的 我在这里
Iona?
IONA: Hi, honey. I'm in here.
- 敢笑我就杀了你 - 怎么回事
Laugh, and I'll deck ya.
What happened?
我60年代既没嗑这么多药
Either it's all those drugs I took in the '60s,
我也没在恋爱
or I am really in love.
(laughs)
你到底在想什么
What do you think?
我只是觉得你很漂亮
Honestly.
Honestly, I think you look great.
- 我跟大妈似的 - 不 是有一点吧 也没关系
Oh, I look like a mother.
No. Well, yeah, a little,
but that's okay.
你看起来很开心
You look happy.
是的
I am.
挺奇怪的 但是… 你见他了?
It's weird, but I...
- 是的 - 好
Did you meet him?
Yeah.
他是个雅皮 但人很好
He's a yuppie,
but he's so nice.
他有工作 是异性恋
He's employed, he's heterosexual.
I swear to God, I'm so far ahead of the game,
我远远领先你 你下次看见我时
我可能会在挑中国品种了
next time you see me, I'll probably be
picking out my china patterns.
(laughs)
你没事吧 不会吧
(crying)
Hey, are you all right?
No, you're not.
- 是因为你妈妈的事? - 不是
What...
What, I blow your mind? No?
男孩的麻烦?
No, that's not it.
It's boy trouble?
- 最坏的? - 更厉害
The worst?
他打发我
Way beyond.
He backed out on me.
他说已经邀请了别人 但他忘了
He said he asked somebody else, and he forgot about it.
我真不敢相信
(crying)
I can't believe it, I can't believe it.
(sighs)
太丢人了
I'm so humiliated.
I could have killed him! I swear!
我发誓我要杀了他
- 我正好赶上了 - 不 别
You know, I just walked right into it.
I know, I know.
爱情糟透了 是不是
(sniffles)
Oh, love is awful, isn't it? Oh.
还好
It's okay.
(crying)
(sniffling)
(sighs and sniffles)
还记得你说要是我要你舞会的裙子 你就给我
You remember when I...
and when you said that-that, um,
if I wanted your prom dress, I could have it?
我想要
Mm-hmm.
Well, I need it.
I want it.
- 要来干吗 - 我就是要
What for?
(sighs)
I just need it.
好吧
(sniffles)
Okay.
是你的了
It's yours.
(rhythmic drumbeat)
(upbeat music playing)
?
(whirring)
天哪 看看你
Oh, God, look at you.
又是第一名 你的男伴看见你会摔到地上的
Another first.
Your guy's going to fall through the floor when he comes in.
- 他不会的 - 肯定会的!
No, he won't.
是真的不会 他不会来的
The hell he's not.
No, he really won't.
- 什么 - 没事的
He's not coming.
What?
- 我要走了 - 一个人?
It's okay.
I'm gonna go.
是的 我不伤心
Alone?
Yeah, I'm not sad about it.
我是说 我是有点受伤
I'm not hurt.
I mean, you know, I am hurt a little bit,
但我知道要是我不做 我会更难受
but I know if I don't do it, I'll just feel a lot worse.
我要进去 走一圈 再走出来回家
I'm just gonna go in, walk in, walk out,
你确定?
and come home.
You sure?
我是想让他们知道我是打不倒的
(sighs)
I just want to let them know that they didn't break me.
("If You Leave" by Orchestral Manoeuvres In The Dark playing)
? If you leave, don't leave now ?
? Please don't take my heart away ?
? Promise me just one more night ?
? And we'll go our separate ways ?
? We've always had time on our sides ?
? Now it's fading fast ?
张嘴
Open up.
? Every second, every moment
? We've got to, gotta make it last ?
? I touch you once, I touch you twice ?
? I won't let go at any price ?
要是有人想上楼动真格的 就告诉我
STEFF: Well, as soon as
anybody's ready to go upstairs and get serious,
我们才来了一小时
just let me know.
We've only been here an hour.
我们可以上去再下来 好吗
Well, we can go up
and come back down again, Benny, all right?
你看套间了吗?
Did you look at the suite?
一晚才300 本尼 肯定不是宫殿
STEFF: It's 300 bucks a night, Benny.
It's not gonna be a palace, okay?
我们应该再待一会儿 这些人以后就看不到了
I think we should stay for a while.
We're not gonna see these people for much longer.
好了 坚持到最后好吗
Come on, it's kind of the end, okay?
我才不管你做什么
STEFF: I don't give a shit what you do.
? I'll be running the other way... ?
妈的
Oh, damn.
My God.
- 你来了 怎么回事? - 就是这么回事
You're here! What happened?!
Well, uh, guess you're looking at it.
你真好看
Oh, wow, you look great.
谢谢 你太好看了 我呼吸不了了
Thanks, you, uh, you look stunning.
Really, it's, it's, it's breathtaking.
听着 我想让你知道 除了我出现在这聚会以外
No, and listen, I want you to know,
despite my appearance at this function, I remain now,
我现在以及以后
and will always be, a Duck Man.
都会是唐老鸭
我崇拜你
(giggles)
May I admire you?
要是你想的话
Oh, uh, if, if you wish.
我们过去吧
Let's plow.
?
? Oh-oh-oh
? I need you now like I needed you then ?
? You always said we'd still be friends someday ?
? If you leave, I won't cry ?
? I won't waste one single day ?
? But if you leave, don't look back ?
我们跳舞吧
Should we dance?
耳闻过
It wouldn't be unheard of.
? Seven years went under the bridge ?
是不是有点未解之谜 布兰?
? Like time standing still...
A little, uh, lingering doubt perhaps, pal?
你得给她名份 之后就甩了她
You know, you gotta give her credit, though.
I mean, after you dumped her,
她发现她这辈子最好的约会…
she certainly went out and found herself what
I'd have to say is probably the most
interesting date that her generation...
什泰夫
Steff.
你能买到一切 却买不到她 这是你最受不了的
You buy everything, Steff.
You couldn't buy her, though.
- 我不想听… - 什泰夫
That's what's killing you, isn't it?
Steff. I don't want to listen to this.
好了 什泰夫
That's it, Steff.
她觉得你狗屎不如
She thinks you're shit.
你心里也知道她是对的
And deep down, you know she's right.
- 嗨 - 嗨
Hi.
你不需要我的道歉
You don't need me to say I'm sorry.
一切都过去了 我没事
It's done. It's over with. I'm fine.
如果真是这样 我很欣慰
? You always said...
Oh, well, if that's true, then I'm glad.
? ...we'd meet again ?
? Someday
不是这样的 但也没关系 是不是
It's not true.
It doesn't matter, does it?
你说过 你不能相信不相信你的人
You told me you couldn't believe in somebody
who didn't believe in you; I believed in you.
我一直相信你
Always believed in you.
我只是不相信自己
Just didn't believe in me.
我爱你
I love you.
? I need you now like I needed you then ?
? You always said we'd meet again ?
一直都是
Always.
安迪
Andie.
他是一个人来的
He came here alone.
是的 你说的对 他跟别人不一样
Okay, you're right.
He's not like the others.
要是你现在不去找他 我就再也不带你参加毕业舞会了
If you don't go to him now,
I'm never gonna take you
to another prom ever again, you hear me?
这是难得的浪漫时刻 却被你毁掉了
I mean, this is an incredibly romantic moment
and you're ruining it for me.
? I touch you twice, I won't let go at any price ?
谢谢 唐老鸭
Thanks, Duckie.
去吧
Go ahead.
? We'd meet again someday... ?
布兰!
Blane?
? Oh-oh-oh
? Oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh
? If you leave
? Oh-oh-oh
? Oh, if you leave
? Oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh
? Oh, if you leave...
Captioning sponsored by PARAMOUNT
Captioned by Media Access Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
? Caroline laughs and it's raining all day ?
? She loves to be one of the girls ?
? She lives in the place in the side of our lives ?
? Where nothing is ever put straight ?
? She turns herself round and she smiles and she says ?
? "This is it, that's the end of the joke" ?
? And loses herself in her dreaming and sleep ?
? And her lovers walk through in their cloaks ?
? She's... pretty in pink ?
? Isn't she... pretty in pink? ?
? Isn't she? ?
? All of her lovers all talk of her notes ?
? And the flowers that they never sent ?
? And wasn't she easy? ?
? Isn't she pretty in pink? ?
? The one who insists he was first in the line ?
? Is the last to remember her name ?
? He's walking around in this dress that she wore ?
? She is gone, but the joke's the same ?
? Pretty in pink
? Isn't she... ?
? Pretty in pink?
? Isn't she? ?
? All the favorite rags are worn ?
? And other kinds of uniform
? But kid, you're already free like individuality ?
? You are what she wants to be until tomorrow. ?